Mr. Sweaty and Ms. Sweaty
Do you have this experience too?
just went out a few minutes ago
Sweat pours out like a tap
Wet armpits and wet back
Clothes like from washing machine
Take it out and it's sticky.
Super embarrassing all day
Even more exaggerated at night
Wake up
The pillow is wet
You thought it was just
the hot weather
No, not that simple
What to do if you keep sweating
It may be a warning signal from your body.
I'll tell you right away
Hu Naiwen starts his lecture
I am your old friend, Doctor Hu
I want to share this episode with you
1.There are 3 types of sweating. Why do you sweat when you eat spicy food?
2.Sweaty palms are embarrassing. 1 tea to stop sweating and rùn fèi (Transliteration)
3.Night sweats make the heart age faster. Drink 1 cup to strengthen immunity.
4.Be careful if you sweat on one side of your body, it may cause autonomic nervous system disorders
5.If you don’t sweat but love to eat ice cream, beware of the invasion ofhán xié(Transliteration)
There are 3 types of sweating. Why do you sweat when you eat spicy food?
Do you have these experiences of sweating?
Make yourself beautiful
Going on a date
As soon as went out and basked in the sun
Sweat is like a waterfall
Keep sweating
makeup is almost ruined
Every time take the bus
I'm afraid of myself
Armpit odor
feel so embarrassed that I want to find a hole to hide in.
Sweating can be divided into three types
The first normal sweating
This is the body's natural cooling mechanism.
The second abnormal sweating
Sweating of palms, soles and underarms
It may be related to physical condition
The third type of drug-induced sweating
It's like taking guì zhī tāng (Transliteration)
It makes you sweat
Our episode
Mainly talk about the first two
When you are after exercise
When it's hot or when you're nervous
The body automatically sweats to cool down
There is another situation
It's when you eat certain foods.
It will make you sweat
The editor, do you know the reason?
When eating spicy food?
Bingo
The spicy taste of chili peppers
In traditional Chinese medicine, it is called a pungent flavor.
Its characteristics are
Xīn zhě néng sàn néng rùn néng héng xíng (Transliteration)
It has the function of heat dissipation
It stimulates the dilation of peripheral blood vessels
in the body
This will cause sweat to flow out
Ingredients in chili peppers
Not only can it dissipate heat
It can also accelerate blood circulation
That's why
when you eat spicy food
Your body will get hot and sweaty
No wonder I always eat spicy hotpot
The forehead and nose sweat first
This is a normal physiological reaction
Helps regulate body temperature
Don't worry
The second is abnormal sweating
Like the palms, soles, and armpits
At the slightest movement, you're soaked with sweat.
It may mean that
there is something wrong with your body.
Doctor Hu, does sweating count as detoxing?
Sweating is not entirely detoxification
The main function of sweating is
Help your body
Heat dissipation and body temperature regulation
Especially in sports
or when the weather is hot
Although sweat contains
a small amount of waste
Such as sodium, urea, and so on
But it is the liver and kidneys, not the sweat glands
that are actually responsible for detoxification.
so
Sweating does not mean complete detoxification
Sweaty palms are embarrassing. 1 tea to stop sweating and rùn fèi (Transliteration)
The editor said that every time he went on stage to give a briefing
was so nervous that palms started sweating
Last week, met a client and wanted to shake hands with them.
had to secretly dry my palms first
Otherwise it would be really embarrassing.
Let's talk
Palms, soles, underarms
These three parts sweat
what is going on
The first type is sweating in the palms and soles of feet
Why do hands and feet sweat?
Shāng hán míng lǐlùn (Transliteration) mentioned
Shǒu zú hàn chū zhě(Transliteration)
Wèi rè jù yú wèi(Transliteration)
Shì jīn yè zhī bàng dá yě(Transliteration)
Hands and feet always sweat
This is because rè qì (Transliteration) in the spleen and stomach.
Causes jīn yè (Transliteration)
Unable to secrete normally
The rè (Transliteration) in the spleen and stomach
What is the biggest culprit?
Cool
Greasy
These three strongly flavored foods.
You start in the summer
Ice Coke
ice cream
Shaved ice all included
Eat it once every week
fried chicken
fries
These are either iced or fried
These foods
Your spleen and stomach are either
too cold or too hot.
This leads to
Your hands and feet keep sweating
How to improve sweaty hands and feet
Traditional Chinese medicine has a
Natural antiperspirant
Fossolia Ossis Mastodi, oyster and glutinous rice are three medicines
Grind it into powder
Put it in the powder puff
Come and pat your palms and feet
The sweat can be stopped
Can fans buy them
at Chinese medicine stores?
rest assured
These medicinal materials are available in Chinese medicine stores
Please ask the boss to give you
one or two servings of each herb.
Fossolia Ossis Mastodi
oyster
Sticky rice
Grind them all into powder
Divide into three or four packs
Before going out
Sprinkle on the palms and soles of feet
Even underarms
Fossolia Ossis Mastodiastringes sweat glands
Oysters reduce abnormal sweating
Glutinous rice strengthens the spleen and stops sweating
The second type of underarm odor is very strong
With a wave of hand
colleagues took three steps back.
Armpits in Traditional Chinese Medicine
It is the place where the xīn jīng (Transliteration) passes.
Xīn huǒ wàng (Transliteration)
Sympathetic nervous system hyperactivity
It will turn armpits
into sweat-generating machines.
To get rid of this body odor
There are two ways
First, drink anti-sweat and rùn fèi (Transliteration) tea.
Prepare four ingredients
Codonopsis pilosula
Dwarf Lilyturf Root Tuber
Schisandra chinensis
Fú xiǎo mài(Transliteration)
10g each
Boil them in 1000 ml of water.
Or just brew it with hot water
Simmer it for twenty minutes
One to two cups per day
Stabilize the autonomic nervous system
Reduces underarm sweating
Second, eat less heavy-tasting food
We Chinese medicine call it hòu wèi (Transliteration)
Like Green onion
garlic
onion
barbecue
Very salty and very spicy
These will
Make your sweat smell stronger
It doesn't just make you less feminine
Of course, men too
There is a strong smell of men
More sweat smell
This won't work.
Night sweats make the heart age faster. Drink 1 cup to strengthen immunity.
Traditional Chinese medicine believes hàn wéi xīn zhī yè (Transliteration)
If sweat too much
It's like bleeding for the heart
Prolonged heavy sweating
Excessive burden on the heart
May accelerate heart aging
When you are low on xīn qì (Transliteration)
Abnormal sweating condition
It will start to appear
Different sweating patterns
In fact, it also reflects the different xū (Transliteration)
Traditional Chinese medicine divides sweat into two types:
A kind called zì hàn (Transliteration)
A kind called night sweat
What does zì hàn (Transliteration) mean?
When consciousness is clear
Whether it's day or night
Sweating while awake
This is called zì hàn (Transliteration)
Especially he will
Feeling a little cold
It is called insufficient yáng qì (Transliteration)
Or called yáng xū (Transliteration)
still feel cold even though sweat
This kind of situation needs to replenish yáng xū (Transliteration)
To strengthen the body and regulate qi and blood
This zì hàn (Transliteration) situation is very complicated
Recommended to see a Chinese medicine practitioner
Diagnosis and treatment will be more effective
Let's talk about night sweat
What is night sweat?
Many mothers say
I slept half the night.
I break out in a cold sweat
When I woke up, it was gone
The pillow often
It got a lot wet.
This is typical night sweats.
Is it the case of sweating while sleeping?
And this situation
Mostly related to yīn xū (Transliteration)
When the body's ability to
nourish and regulate becomes poor
The body temperature control is out of control
When sleep
Spontaneous sweating like this
What should do if I keep having night sweats while sleeping?
There is a Chinese medicine prescription called
Shēng mài yǐn(Transliteration)
You can try it.
But still
It is recommended to see a doctor
How to make Shēng mài yǐn (Transliteration)
Shēng mài yǐn (Transliteration)is made of ginseng, Dwarf Lilyturf Root Tuber and schisandra chinensis.
Its serving size is
Three qián (Transliteration) of ginseng
Or three qián (Transliteration)of ginseng root
Schisandra chinensis 20 capsules
Dwarf Lilyturf Root Tuber 1liǎng(Transliteration)
Or a little more doesn't matter
You boil these herbs
into a light soup
Drink it as tea
Especially suitable for summer and early autumn
Not only does it reduce sweat
It can also replenish qi and yǎng yīn (Transliteration)
Improve immunity
If you sweat on one side of your body, it may be autonomic nervous system disorder
There is a kind of sweat that cannot be ignored
Have you ever had the experience of sweating on one side of your body
and not sweating on the other?
It's not a physical issue.
It is likely a typical symptom of autonomic nervous system disorder
Why is sweating related to the autonomic nervous system?
Sweat from the armpits, palms, and soles
They are all controlled by the sympathetic nervous system
Sweating in other surrounding areas
It is controlled by the parasympathetic nervous system
If the autonomic nervous system is out of balance
The body's cooling system
Chaos began to appear
So this place is sweating
That place doesn't sweat.
or sweating on one side of the body
No sweat on the other side
This kind of imbalance
This is autonomic dysfunction
So when you find that one side is sweating
and the other side is not sweating
Don't ignore
Maybe it is
Autonomic Nerve
Send out a distress signal
suggest you see a doctor.
If you don’t sweat but love to eat ice cream, beware of the invasion ofhán xié (Transliteration)
Let’s talk about another
What to do if your body doesn't sweat
Not sweating is actually telling you
The body is already in trouble
The inability to sweat is relatedto
both external cold and the invasion of hán qì (Transliteration) in the body.
Office workers every day
Stay in the air-conditioned room
Busy work makes you less exercise
Over time
Functions of sweat glands and pores
It gradually degenerates
It becomes less prone to sweating
This is not only
Affects our
Ability to regulate body temperature
And it will also make the reaction to hot and cold
Became slow
The problem is not just the air conditioning
And the hán qì (Transliteration) you eat
Do you love ice cream
in summer?
Smoothies
Hand shake drink
These cold foods
It will make your stomach feel cold
As a result, the sweating function becomes worse
The result was
The Hán qì (Transliteration) can't be expelled
The Yáng qì (Transliteration) can't rise.
After a long time
Makes you feel groggy
Neck stiffness
Poor appetite
Maybe it will
Heat stroke
Do you think this video is useful?
Don't forget to click "Super Thanks" below the video
Your encouragement
It is our motivation to continue working hard